<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="cit_doctor_hello_dialog_11">
		<text>Yes? What do you want? Strelok? Is that you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_hello_dialog_21">
		<text>I've told you everything that I know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_0">
		<text>Strelok? I think you have me confused, old man. I've heard you have information about the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_1">
		<text>Confused? Oh... I might have the information you seek, but I'll want you to do something in return.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_11">
		<text>Of course. What would you have me do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_2">
		<text>The Zone has taken a heavy toll on me over the years, so I spend my final days here, where it's quiet, but I would rather enjoy seeing my old friends once again. I fear Strelok and Guide may be dead, but I would very much like to speak with Fang and Ghost while there is still time. If you can find them and bring them here, I would most appreciate your efforts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_21">
		<text>How long have you lived out here? Fang and Ghost are legendary stalkers, but they're both long dead. Fang was killed by a mercenary named Scar at the army warehouses, and Ghost was found underneath Yantar in lab X16 about a year later. Did you really not know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_3">
		<text>They're both dead? Are you sure? I just... Oh, alright... What is it that you want to know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_31">
		<text>Really? Are you telling me that easily? I feel you're just wasting my time, old man.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_4">
		<text>Wait! Don't go... I just didn't expect them to finish badly. When Strelok last came to visit, he gave me a key and coordinates to a stash in Pripyat. He hasn't visited in years, so I don't suppose he's fared much better. He was saying something about the Monolith. I didn't understand much of it, and I'm not too sure he did, either. Here, take it. And one more thing... He spent a lot of time searching for clues of a conspiracy in underground labs; some kind of secret cover-up, I believe. Perhaps you'll find your answers there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_41">
		<text>I see. Thanks. I appreciate your help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_5">
		<text>Now, go. Leave an old man in peace.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
