<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="st_dev_cigarettes_mechta_blue_name">
		<text>Sigarettes «Dream blue»</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dev_cigarettes_mechta_blue_descr">
		<text>Cheap locally produced cigarettes that enter the Zone through soldiers and the perimeter. Smoking does not provide any benefits other than blunting the feeling of hunger, but in return it takes away health and rewards psychological dependence.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dev_cigarettes_mechta_red_name">
		<text>Sigarettes «Dream red»</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dev_cigarettes_mechta_red_descr">
		<text>Cheap locally produced cigarettes that enter the Zone through soldiers and the perimeter. Red cigarettes are somewhat stronger than blue ones. Smoking does not provide any benefits other than blunting the feeling of hunger, but in return it takes away health and rewards psychological dependence.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_item_water_bottle">
		<text>Water Bottle «Carpathians»</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_item_water_bottle_descr">
		<text>The most ordinary drinking water that stalkers often take with them. Quenches thirst well and restores strength a little.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_energy_drink_nonstop">
		<text>Energy drink «Non Stop»</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_energy_drink_nonstop_descr">
		<text>Excellent energy drink "Non Stop". It contains caffeine, taurine and a powerful vitamin complex that relieves fatigue and adds strength. Unable to take even a step? Then this is exactly what you need.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_antirad">
		<text>Anti-radiation drugs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_antirad_descr">
		<text>Mexaminum radiation protection drugs are common in the Zone. When used, this drug induces contraction of peripheral blood vessels and oxygen deprivation, which serves to treat and prevent radiation exposure. The drug does not have severe side effects, although isolated cases of mild nausea, dizziness, cramps and stomach pain have been reported.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bandage">
		<text>Bandage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bandage_descr">
		<text>A normal elastic bandage used to stop bleeding and prevent infection of wounds. For regular bleeding, carefully apply the bandage to the wound. For arterial bleeding, urgently tie the bandage around the affected area.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_binocular_descr">
		<text>Modular binoculars without any additions. Useful in the Zone in that they allow its owner to observe things from a distance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_binocular_name">
		<text>Binoculars</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_knife_descr">
		<text>Standard combat knife with a serrated blade. Useful for breaking open boxes and silently taking down enemies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_knife">
		<text>Combat knife</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bread">
		<text>Bread</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bread_descr">
		<text>No bakers have ever been identified in the Zone, but this bread is neither contaminated nor radioactive, being fresh and quite edible. At least no complaints have been reported thus far.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_conserva">
		<text>'Tourist's Breakfast'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_conserva_descr">
		<text>Presumably, these canned goods were looted by stalkers from an army ration depot. Without any kind of label on the can, it's hard to say for sure. Should still be good to eat, if you believe the best before date.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector1">
		<text>'Echo' detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector1_descr">
		<text>This dated anomalous activity detector produces an alarm signal when anomalous particles enter a special chamber as you approach an anomaly. It can also register the presence of artefacts and measure the distance to the nearest one. The distance is indicated by the frequency of the sound the detector emits. To switch to artefact search mode, open the device's front cover. Due to its simple design, Echo can only be used to locate the most common artefacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector2">
		<text>'Bear' detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector3">
		<text>'Veles' detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector3_descr">
		<text>A next generation scientific detection scanner. Thanks to three modernized detection chambers, the position of artefacts is shown on a special display screen. When closed, the device registers only radiation and anomalies. To switch to artefact search mode, open the front LED display. When in search mode, the detector is capable of locating all artefacts known to science.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector4">
		<text>'Svarog' detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector4_descr">
		<text>A prototype of an expanded functionality anomalous frequency scanner. This device comes with a program used to identify static areas of anomalous activity stored in its database, while retaining the ability to locate artefacts. The position of anomalous areas and artefacts is displayed on a special screen. The artefact search mode, which can be activated by opening the front LED display, has been modified to detect anomalous formations currently unknown to science.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_torch_descr">
		<text>A standard head-mounted flashlight. Useful for stalkers who find themselves out and about after dark, but may attract trouble if used unwisely.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_torch_name">
		<text>Headlamp</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_anabiotic">
		<text>Anabiotics</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_antidot">
		<text>Antidote</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_antidot_descr">
		<text>The IP2 antitoxin is a complex drug comprising several antidotes, including metoclopramidum, pyridoxine, thiamine, riboxin and other pharmaceuticals. The drug is used to inject a range of antibiotics to neutralize natural poisons, together with synthetic poison absorbers, into the bloodstream. IP2 is not particularly popular in the Zone, as most stalkers rely on a gas mask and a protective suit, there are still those who have a pack of this antidote stashed away. The effects of the drug are long-lasting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_booster">
		<text>Hercules</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_coagulant">
		<text>Vinca</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_coagulant_descr">
		<text>Ukrainian Vikasolum; an artificial equivalent of vitamin K. The main purpose of this drug is to increase blood coagulation speed. In great demand among stalkers who want slow-healing wounds and lacerations inflicted by mutants to close up faster. The effects of the drug are long-lasting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_psy_blockade">
		<text>Psi-block</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_psy_blockade_descr">
		<text>A drug that blocks avalanche-like nerve impulses. Consumption induces short-term loss of all emotion. Used exclusively in the Zone to counteract the effects of anomalous psi-fields. The effects of the drug are long-lasting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_radioprotector">
		<text>Radioprotectant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_energy_drink">
		<text>Energy drink</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_energy_drink_descr">
		<text>Often used by stalkers on long trips when no breaks can be afforded. The drink contains easily digestible carbohydrates, as well as drugs that stimulate the release of adrenaline into the bloodstream.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_guitar_descr">
		<text>A trusty guitar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_guitar_name">
		<text>Guitar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kolbasa">
		<text>Diet sausage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kolbasa_descr">
		<text>For better or worse, this sausage, a mix of chicken and a soy substitute, is often a stalker's breakfast, lunch, and dinner in one. Can be stored for a long time due to high preservative content.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit">
		<text>First-aid kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_army">
		<text>Army medkit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_army_descr">
		<text>A specialized medical kit for providing first aid to combat casualties. The kit includes blood coagulants based on menadione, painkillers, antibiotics and immunostimulants, as well as a kit for removing bullets and fragments from the body. This medkit is issued to army personnel as standard and is sometimes used by Duty forces.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_descr">
		<text>A general purpose single-use medical kit. Handy for treating various injuries: wounds, bruises, regular and chemical burns, and various types of poisoning. In demand among stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_science">
		<text>Scientific medkit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_science_descr">
		<text>A medical kit designed specifically for use in the Zone. The kit contains products for handling wounds, as well as preventing the development of radiation poisoning and reducing accumulated radiation in the body. Contains Vikasolum, Batilolum and Naphazoline, unlike other medkits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pda_descr">
		<text>Might have useful information on it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pda_name">
		<text>PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pda_spore_name">
		<text>Spore's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_vodka">
		<text>Cossacks Vodka</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_vodka_descr">
		<text>Made by GSC. Goes down easy and considerably lowers the effects of radiation. Should be enjoyed in moderation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector2_descr">
		<text>This last generation anomalous activity detector can be used to locate anomalous formations and has a colour diode panel, which not only indicates the direction of artefacts, but also measures the distance to them. To switch to artefact search mode, open the device's front cover. Unfortunately, the device is programmed with a somewhat outdated list of detectable artefacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_anabiotic_descr">
		<text>An experimental drug developed by Professor Ozersky for scientific research teams working in the Zone. At its core, the drug contains tetrodotoxin, known colloquially as 'zombie powder', which causes a complete shutdown of the body's central nervous system that may allow people to survive emissions outside cover. The drug has not undergone clinical or field testing, which puts its effectiveness in doubt and raises the issue of possible side effects.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bolt">
		<text>Bolt</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_booster_descr">
		<text>The main component of this product is an anabolic androgen, an artificial steroid, the chemical composition of which resembles testosterone. Often used by stalkers during long raids to reduce muscle fatigue. Significantly increases weight-carrying capacity. The effects of the drug are long-lasting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_radioprotector_descr">
		<text>B190 Indraline radioprotectant, included in medkits issued to nuclear power plant personnel. Used in the Zone instead of the excessively toxic PC1 cystamine hydrochloride, repeated use of which often caused death. Reduces the effects of gamma radiation on live tissue. Best consumed before exposure, as effects are not instant. The effects of the drug are long-lasting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_harmonica_name">
		<text>Harmonica</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_harmonica_descr">
		<text>For blues and prison romance lovers.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_itm_deployable_mgun_name">
		<text>Deployable RP-74</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_deployable_mgun_desc">
		<text>This belt-fed machine gun is a portable modification with a complex two-stage feeding system. Despite its weight and low precision, this LMG has found admirers in the Zone. Used primarily to fight off outnumbering enemy forces during faction conflicts and clear out mutant lairs.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_memory_stick_name">
		<text>Memory stick</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_equ_backpack_name">
		<text>Backpack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_equ_backpack_desc">
		<text>A regular water resistant backpack. It has high popularity among stalkers who travel around the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_equ_smallpack_name">
		<text>Small backpack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_equ_smallpack_desc">
		<text>Small backpack usually worn by rookies. The inside has been modified to keep water out. A crude but practical solution.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_equ_smilpack_name">
		<text>Duffel bag</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_equ_smilpack_desc">
		<text>A cylindrical bag made from canvas, used by the military for well over a hundred years.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_equ_milpack_name">
		<text>Combat backpack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_equ_milpack_desc">
		<text>A combat backpack used by the military, often to store additional munitions and medical supplies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_equ_touristpack_name">
		<text>Tourist backpack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_equ_touristpack_desc">
		<text>A tourist's backpack with a lot of storage space. Not very popular due to its cumbersome size.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_water">
		<text>Water</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_water_descr">
		<text>Clean and refreshing water. It can negate radioactivity received from Zone-produced food or help sober up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_flashlight_name">
		<text>Flashlight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_flashlight_desc">
		<text>A battery-operated LED flashlight.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_device_nvg_1_name">
		<text>NVG «Owl» 1st gen</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_nvg_1_descr">
		<text>An ancient version of the military NVG, which can be obtained relatively inexpensively. It is a monocular and is characterized by a poor picture and moderate consumption</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_nvg_2_name">
		<text>NVG «Owl» 2nd gen</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_nvg_2_descr">
		<text>The more advanced version consumes less energy, but the weight has increased slightly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_nvg_3_name">
		<text>NVG «Owl» 3rd gen</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_nvg_3_descr">
		<text>A regular NVG for groups of elite special forces and paratroopers, shows an excellent noise-proof picture, but consumes much more energy, however, special-purpose groups do not need a long working time. Significantly reduced in weight relative to the second model.</text>
	</string>	

	<string id="st_device_torch_bad_name">
		<text>Headlamp «Pioneer»</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_torch_bad_descr">
		<text>The cheapest and mass-produced series of headlamps from the Pioneer company. \n%c[255,238,153,26]Light beam range: unknown. \n%c[255,238,153,26]Angle: unknown.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_torch_mid_name">
		<text>Headlamp «Pioneer M»</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_torch_mid_descr">
		<text>An upgraded version of the well-known headlamp, although it is not enough for the realities of dark dungeons. \n%c[255,238,153,26]Light beam range: 8 meters. \n%c[255,238,153,26]Angle: 55 degrees.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_torch_wid_name">
		<text>Headlamp «Pioneer WM»</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_torch_wid_descr">
		<text>A special version of the headlamp from the Pioneer company, equipped with a spotlight-type illuminator, but unfortunately, for lack of a good power source, it still shines nearby. \n%c[255,238,153,26]Light beam range: 8 meters. \n%c[255,238,153,26]Angle: 105 degrees.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_torch_far_name">
		<text>Headlamp «Pioneer SF»</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_torch_far_descr">
		<text>A version of a headlamp designed for military and special units. It differs from its predecessors in that the focused spotlight shines much further. \n%c[255,238,153,26]Light beam range: 20 meters. \n%c[255,238,153,26]Angle: 60 degrees.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_torch_top_name">
		<text>Headlamp «Pioneer SW»</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_torch_top_descr">
		<text>The latest modification of the Pioneer company's headlamp, which was created specifically for soldiers guarding the perimeter. It has everything you need: a powerful power source and the most favorable lighting characteristics, which, however, negatively affected its mass. \n%c[255,238,153,26]Light beam range: 20 meters. \n%c[255,238,153,26]Angle: 105 degrees.</text>
	</string>	

	<string id="st_itm_battery_detectors_simple">
		<text>Batteries for the detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_battery_detectors_simple_descr">
		<text>Energy-intensive batteries for early models of artifact detectors of the "Response" and "Bear" type.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_battery_detectors_elite">
		<text>Battery for the detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_battery_detectors_elite_descr">
		<text>It is used in detectors of the "Veles" and "Svarog" class.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_battery_torch">
		<text>Packaging of batteries</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_battery_torch_descr">
		<text>Standard packaging of batteries for all sorts of small devices, which may be enough for several uses.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_itm_battery_actor_pda">
		<text>Battery for PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_itm_battery_actor_pda_descr">
		<text>A standard energy-intensive battery for a PDA, which lasts for about a day.</text>
	</string>	
	
	<string id="st_device_bolt">
		<text>Bolt</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_device_bolt_descr">
		<text>Stalkers use them mainly to "probe" the boundaries of anomalies. Rumor has it that to pick up a brand new, not rusty bolt is a great misfortune.</text>
	</string>		
</string_table>
