<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_factions_historic">
		<text>Factions (Historic)</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_factions_historic_final_day">
		<text>Final Day</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_factions_historic_final_day_text">
		<text>
			%c[guide_blue]Final Day%c[default] were a faction of scientists, also known as %c[guide_blue]Last Day%c[default], or as "%c[guide_blue]wild stalkers%c[default]".\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Information%c[default]
			\nThey believed that the Zone would ultimately bring about the end of the world, expanding into and claiming ever more land with each passing emission.\n
			\nAside from their fascination with hunting zombified stalkers for research purposes, and that their now-forgotten leader was assassinated by a stalker called Ghost, little else is known about them.\n
			\nWith their activity occurring shortly after the emission that wiped out much of Clear Sky, it is possible they were a small splinter group - survivors who became unhinged from what they had witnessed.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Statistics%c[default]\n
			\n• Leaders: Unknown\n• Headquarters: Unknown\n• Colours: Unknown\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Trivia%c[default]
			\n• All that is known about this faction is from game design documents.
			\n• This faction was cut from S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Shadow of Chernobyl.
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_factions_historic_renegade">
		<text>Renegade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_factions_historic_renegade_text">
		<text>
			%c[guide_blue]Renegades%c[default] were some of the most despicable stalkers in the Zone.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Information%c[default]
			\nHaving no limits or morals, they consisted mainly of stalkers who had committed crimes so terrible that their original factions had cast them out.\n
			\nThe only law they respected was one of force, preying on the weak at the perimeters of the Zone, often those who were too young and inexperienced to stand any chance against them.\n
			\nDriven into the marshes by their numerous enemies, it was only in the face of Clear Sky that their desire to survive forced these jackals to unite as a faction of their own.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Statistics%c[default]\n
			\n• Leaders: Unknown\n• Headquarters: Great Swamp\n• Colours: Various\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Trivia%c[default]
			\n• They appeared very briefly in S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Clear Sky.
			\n• This faction only existed so the player could befriend bandits.
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_factions_historic_csky">
		<text>«Clear Sky»</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_factions_historic_csky_text">
		<text>
			%c[guide_blue]Clear Sky%c[default] — a semi-mythical group that once lived in Large Swamps. According to rumors, the guard was completely destroyed during a suicidal assault on the center of the Zone.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Information%c[default]
			\nRumor has it that their goal was to study the Zone separately from government scientists.\n
			\nThis group was somehow connected with the legendary stalker named Scar, however, many question both his existence and everything «Clear Sky».\n
			\n• Leaders: Unknown\n• Headquarters: Great Swamp\n• Colours: blue\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Trivia%c[default]
			\n• They appeared very briefly in S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Clear Sky.
		</text>
	</string>		
	
</string_table>